George Korson Collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Subseries L: Audio tape transcripts and song logs
    - AFC 2003/011: SR020 (transcripts), August 9, 1957 (Box-folder 70/3)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR021 (transcript), August 8, 1957 (Box-folder 70/4)
      Includes a newspaper clipping in the folder
    - AFC 2003/011: SR022 (transcript), August 12, 1957 (Box-folder 70/5)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR023 (transcripts), August 28, 1957 (Box-folder 70/6)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR024-025 (transcript), August 23, 1957 (Box-folder 70/7)
      The transcripts for SR024 and SR025 were created as a single, continuous unit.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR026 (transcripts), August 10, 1957; August 27, 1957; August 28, 1957 (Box-folder 70/8)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR027 (transcript), August 20, 1957 (Box-folder 70/9)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR028 (transcript), August 23, 1957 (Box-folder 70/10)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR029 (transcript), August 29, 1957 (Box-folder 70/11)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR030 (transcripts), August 21, 1957 (Box-folder 70/12)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR031 (transcripts), August 27, 1957 (Box-folder 70/13)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR032 (transcript), August 24, 1957 (Box-folder 70/14)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR033 (transcript), August 30, 1957 (Box-folder 70/15)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR034 (transcript), September 3, 1957 (Box-folder 70/16)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR035 (transcripts), September 5, 1957 (Box-folder 70/17)
      Duplicated in part on AFC 2003/011: SR058.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR035-036 (transcript), September 5, 1957 (Box-folder 70/18)
      The transcripts for SR035 and SR036 were created as a single, continuous unit.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR037 (transcript), September 6, 1957 (Box-folder 71/1)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR038 (transcripts), September 9, 1957 (Box-folder 71/2)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR039 (transcript), September 20, 1957 (Box-folder 71/3)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR040 (transcript), September 6, 1957 (Box-folder 71/4)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR041 (transcript), September 23, 1957 (Box-folder 71/5)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR042 (transcript), September 18, 1957 (Box-folder 71/6)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR043 (transcript), September 21, 1957 (Box-folder 71/7)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR044 (transcript), September 29, 1957 (Box-folder 71/8)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR045 (transcript), October 2, 1957 (Box-folder 71/9)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR046 (transcripts), October 1, 1957 (Box-folder 71/10)
      A manuscript item in folder could be Korson's handwriting.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR047 (transcripts), September 12 and 23, 1957; October 4, 1957 (Box-folder 71/11)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR048 (transcript), September 24, 1957 (Box-folder 71/12)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR048-049 (transcript), October 15, 1957 (Box-folder 71/13)
      The transcripts for this subject's two interviews (begun on AFC 2003/011: SR048 and completed on AFC 2003/011: SR049) were created as a single, continuous unit.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR049 (transcript), September 7, 1957 (Box-folder 71/14)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR050 (transcripts), October 2, 5, and 8, 1957 (Box-folder 71/15)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR051 (transcript), September 18, 1957 (Box-folder 71/16)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR052 (transcript), October 13, 1957 (Box-folder 71/17)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR053 (transcript), October 6, 1957 (Box-folder 71/18)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR054-057 (transcripts), March 31, 1955 (Box-folder 71/19)
      The transcripts for AFC 2003/011: SR054-057 were created as a single, continuous unit.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR058 (transcripts), August 12-13 and 20, 1957; September 5, 9, and 18, 1957; October 5, 1957 (Box-folder 71/20)
      The recording is a compilation reel of other recordings.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR059 (transcripts), August 12 and 27, 1957 (Box-folder 72/1)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR060 (transcripts), August 3, 1957; September 22, 1957 (Box-folder 72/2)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR061 (transcripts), August 13 and 27, 1957 (Box-folder 72/3)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR062 (transcripts), September 12, 1957; September 18, 1957 (Box-folder 72/4)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR063 (transcript), September 22, 1957 (Box-folder 72/5)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR064 (transcript), September 20, 1957 (Box-folder 72/6)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR065 (transcript), October 5, 1957 (Box-folder 72/7)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR066 (transcripts), July 1, 1958 (Box-folder 72/8)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR067 (transcript), August 28, 1958 (Box-folder 72/9)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR068 (transcript), October 30, 1958 (Box-folder 72/10)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR069 (transcript), March 31, 1962 (Box-folder 72/11)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR070 (transcript), March 31, 1962 (Box-folder 72/12)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR071-072 (transcript), November 22, 2965 (Box-folder 72/13)
      The transcripts for AFC 2003/011: SR071 and AFC 2003/011: SR072 were created as a single, continuous unit (and as a rough draft only).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR073 (transcript), October 15, 1966 (Box-folder 72/14)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR074-076 (transcript), May 9, 1957 (Box-folder 72/15)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR078 (Box-folder 72/16)
      Children's songs. Song log, plus introductions to and lyrics for the songs.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR079 (Box-folder 72/17)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR080 (Box-folder 72/18)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR081 (Box-folder 72/19)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR082 (Box-folder 72/20)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR083 (Box-folder 72/21)
      Children's songs. Song log, plus lyrics for the songs.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR084 (Box-folder 72/22)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR085 (Box-folder 73/1)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR086 (Box-folder 73/2)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Song log only.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR087 (Box-folder 73/3)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR088 (Box-folder 73/4)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, locations, and brief notes. Reel 1 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR089 (Box-folder 73/5)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, locations, and brief notes. Reel 2 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR090 (Box-folder 73/6)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, and locations. Reel 3 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR091 (Box-folder 73/7)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, and locations. Reel 4 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR092 (Box-folder 73/8)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, and locations. Reel 5 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR093 (Box-folder 73/9)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, and locations. Reel 6 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR094 (Box-folder 73/10)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, and locations. Reel 7 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR095 (Box-folder 73/11)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, locations, and brief note. Reel 8 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR096 (Box-folder 73/12)
      Bituminous miners' songs. Concordance, song list, performer names, locations, and brief note. Reel 9 of 9 reels of the "George Korson Duplication Project" (LWO 3960).
    - AFC 2003/011: SR097 (Box-folder 73/13)
      Coal miners' songs. The document "Tape Recordings Reel List" identifies these as "Bituminous miners' songs."
    - AFC 2003/011: SR098 (Box-folder 73/14)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR099 (Box-folder 73/15)
      Coal miners' folk songs, sung by Joe Glazer. Song log only.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR100-103, circa 1962 (Box-folder 73/16)
      Reading of The child's book of folklore, by Marion Vallat Emrich and George Gershon Korson.
    - AFC 2003/011: SR104 (transcript) (Box-folder 73/17)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR105 (transcript) (Box-folder 73/18)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR106 (transcript) (Box-folder 73/19)
    - AFC 2003/011: SR107 (Box-folder 73/20)
      Railroad songs. Song log only.
  - Subseries M: Research and reference
    Publications, offprints, drafts, and related materials. The contents of the folder "Pennsylvania: maps (oversized)" are now housed in oversize folder 1.
    - American Folklore Society (Box-folder 74/1)
    - Amish (Box-folder 74/2)
    - Aunt Molly Jackson (Box-folder 74/3)
    - Canals (Box-folder 74/4)
    - Casey Jones (Box-folder 74/5)
    - Con Carbon (Box-folder 74/6)
    - Coal: surveys (Box-folder 74/7)
    - Coal: preprints from Bureau of Mines Minerals Yearbook, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 74/8)
    - Coal: miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Box-folder 74/9)
    - Coal: miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Box-folder 74/10)
    - Coal breakers (Box-folder 74/11)
    - Coal carving (Box-folder 74/12)
    - Coal mines and mining: miners' circulars, Department of the Interior, 1916-1920 (Box-folder 74/13)
    - Coal mines and mining: Business Review (Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia), 1949-1956 (Box-folder 75/1)
    - Coal mines and mining: U.S. Treasury Department publications (Box-folder 75/2)
    - Coal mines and mining: U.S. Department of Labor (Children's Bureau) publications (Box-folder 75/3)
    - Coal mines and mining: U.S. Department of the Interior publications (Box-folder 75/4)
    - Coal mines and mining: U.S. Department of Commerce publication, 1928 (Box-folder 75/5)
    - Coal mines and mining: miscellaneous (1 of 3) (Box-folder 75/6)
    - Coal mines and mining: miscellaneous (2 of 3) (Box-folder 75/7)
    - Coal mines and mining: miscellaneous (3 of 3) (Box-folder 75/8)
    - Conestoga wagons (Box-folder 75/9)
    - Ephrata (Box-folder 75/10)
    - Folk art (Box-folder 75/11)
    - Folk festivals: plans, publicity, and programs (Box-folder 75/12)
    - Folk festivals: miscellaneous writings (Box-folder 75/13)
    - Folk heroes (Box-folder 75/14)
    - Folk language (Box-folder 75/15)
    - Folklore: animals (Box-folder 75/16)
    - Folklore and education (Box-folder 76/1)
    - Folklore (Box-folder 76/2)
    - Folklore: Louisiana (Box-folder 76/3)
    - Folklore: Minnesota (Box-folder 76/4)
    - Folklore and literature (Box-folder 76/5)
    - Folklore: miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Box-folder 76/6)
    - Folklore: miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Box-folder 76/7)
    - Folklore: ethnic studies (Box-folder 76/8)
    - Folklore: Christmas (1 of 2) (Box-folder 76/9)
    - Folklore: Christmas (2 of 2) (Box-folder 76/10)
    - Folklore: luck (Box-folder 76/11)
    - Folklore: mines (Box-folder 76/12)
    - Folklore scholars (Box-folder 76/13)
    - Folklore societies (Box-folder 77/1)
    - Folk medicine (Box-folder 77/2)
    - Folk music (1 of 2) (Box-folder 77/3)
    - Folk music (2 of 2) (Box-folder 77/4)
    - Folk songs: discographies (Box-folder 77/5)
    - Folk songs: publications with transcribed music and/or lyrics (Box-folder 77/6)
    - Folk songs (1 of 2) (Box-folder 77/7)
    - Folk songs (2 of 2) (Box-folder 77/8)
    - Folk songs: Pennsylvania (1 of 2) (Box-folder 77/9)
    - Folk songs: Pennsylvania (2 of 2) (Box-folder 77/10)
    - Folk songs: American (1 of 2) (Box-folder 77/11)
    - Folk songs: American (2 of 2) (Box-folder 78/1)
    - Folk songs: mining (Box-folder 78/2)
    - Folk songs: Native American (Box-folder 78/3)
    - Folk tales (1 of 2) (Box-folder 78/4)
    - Folk tales (2 of 2) (Box-folder 78/5)
    - Stephen Foster (Box-folder 78/6)
    - Games (Box-folder 78/7)
    - Genealogy (Box-folder 78/8)
    - Humor (Box-folder 78/9)
    - Labor unions (Box-folder 78/10)
    - Lattimer massacre (Box-folder 79/1)
    - Lehigh Coal and Navigation Company (Box-folder 79/2)
    - John L. Lewis (Box-folder 79/3)
    - Mine disasters (Box-folder 79/4)
    - Molly Maguires (Box-folder 79/5)
    - Mother Goose (Box-folder 79/6)
    - Mother Jones (Box-folder 79/7)
    - Musical instruments (Box-folder 79/8)
    - Pennsylvania (1 of 2) (Box-folder 79/9)
    - Pennsylvania (2 of 2) (Box-folder 79/10)
    - Pennsylvania: Schuylkill County (Box-folder 79/11)
    - Pennsylvania: Mauch Chunk (Box-folder 80/1)
    - Pennsylvania: miscellaneous publications (1 of 2) (Box-folder 80/2)
    - Pennsylvania: miscellaneous publications (2 of 2) (Box-folder 80/3)
    - Pennsylvania Folklore Society (Box-folder 80/4)
    - Pennsylvania German humor (Box-folder 80/5)
    - Pennsylvania German cooking (Box-folder 80/6)
    - Pennsylvania German hex signs (Box-folder 80/7)
    - Pennsylvania Germans: miscellaneous (1 of 3) (Box-folder 80/8)
    - Pennsylvania Germans: miscellaneous (2 of 3) (Box-folder 80/9)
    - Pennsylvania Germans: miscellaneous (3 of 3) (Box-folder 80/10)
    - Quakers (Society of Friends) (Box-folder 80/11)
    - Railroads (Box-folder 80/12)
    - Red Cross (1 of 2) (Box-folder 81/1)
    - Red Cross (2 of 2) (Box-folder 81/2)
    - Fannie Selling (Box-folder 81/3)
    - Street cries (Box-folder 81/4)
    - Swedes (Box-folder 81/5)
    - United Mine Workers Union: welfare and retirement fund (including health issues) (1 of 2) (Box-folder 81/6)
    - United Mine Workers Union: welfare and retirement fund (including health issues) (2 of 2) (Box-folder 81/7)
    - United Mine Workers Union: miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Box-folder 81/8)
    - United Mine Workers Union: miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Box-folder 81/9)
    - Conrad Weiser (Box-folder 81/10)
  - Subseries N: Scrapbooks
    Exterior measurements for scrapbooks are approximate.
    - Allentown Chronicle and News: articles, 1931-1932, 10 in. x 8 1/2 in. x 1 3/4 in. (Box 82)
      Includes newspaper clippings: Korson's columns "A Stranger in Allentown" and "Rambles in Allentown," plus other articles by other writers on coal and other industries.
    - Pennsylvania Folk Festival: articles, 1935, 14 1/2 in. x 11 1/4 in. x 1 1/4 in. (Box 83)
      The first Pennsylvania Folk Festival, held in Allentown. Includes newspaper clippings with handwritten notations. The label on the front cover says "First annual folk festival, Allentown 1935." See folder 61/6.
    - Pennsylvania Folk Festival: articles (scrapbook 1 of 2), 1936, 16 in. x 11 1/2 in. x 3/4 in. (Box 84)
      The second Pennsylvania Folk Festival, held in Lewisburg. Includes newspaper clippings. The label on the front cover says "The Pennsylvania Folk Festival in Memorial Stadium, Bucknell University, Lewisburg, Pa., Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday, July 30--31--August 1--2--1936." Includes articles on various regional folk festivals in Pennsylvania. See folder 61/7-9 and folder 62/1.
    - Pennsylvania Folk Festival: articles (scrapbook 2 of 2), 1936, 16 in. x 17 1/2 in. x 2 1/4 in. (Box 85)
      The second Pennsylvania Folk Festival, held in Lewisburg. Includes newspaper clippings. The label on the front cover says "Pennsylvania Folk Festival, Bucknell University, Memorial Stadium, Lewisburg, July 30, 31-Aug. 1, 2." Includes articles on various regional folk festivals in Pennsylvania. See box-folders 61/7-9 and box-folder 62/1.
    - Songs and ballads of the anthracite miner: reviews, circa 1927-1934, 10 in. x 12 in. x 2 1/4 in. (Box 86)
      Includes newspaper clippings. See box-folder 60/14.
    - Minstrels of the mine patch: reviews, circa 1938-1966, 13 1/4 in. x 10 in. x 3/4 in. (Box 87)
      Includes newspaper clippings and related materials. See box-folder 59/8.
    - Coal dust on the fiddle: reviews, circa 1943-1965, 16 in. x 11 1/2 in. x 1 in. (Box 88)
      Includes newspaper clippings and related materials. See box-folder 59/9.
    - At his side: reviews, circa 1942-1945, 16 1/2 in. x 12 1/4 in. x 1 3/4 in. (Box 89)
      Includes newspaper clippings and related materials. See box-folder 59/10 for more reviews.
    - Black rock: reviews, circa 1960-1964, 14 1/2 in. x 12 in. x 1 1/2 in. (Box 90)
      Includes newspaper clippings and related materials. See box-folder 60/7-9 for more reviews.
    - Biographical materials, circa 1957-1964, 12 in. x 10 in. x 1/2 in. (Box 91)
      Newspaper clippings, plus a program for the Pennsylvania Folklore Society fall meeting (October 16-17, 1959) and a list of books purchased from Boochever Memorial funds that were (at the time) available at the American National Red Cross headquarters library.
    - Biographical materials, circa 1965-1966, 10 1/4 in. x 13 1/2 in. x 1 in. (Box 92)
      Newspaper clippings.
    - George Korson: obituaries, circa 1967, 11 1/2 in. x 9 3/4 in. x 1 1/4 in. (Box 93)
      Newspaper clippings of Korson's obituaries, as well as obituaries reprinted in various publications. See box-folder 61/5.
  - Subseries O: Oversize materials and unframed items (manuscripts)
    Items that arrived at AFC in frames were unframed and treated by Library of Congress Conservation staff in 2005.
    - Unframed manuscript 1, 14 3/4 in. x 10 3/4 in. or smaller (Box-folder 94/1)
      "A Miner's Prayer." Copy of a broadside originally printed by C. Erb, York, Pennsylvania, in 1904.
    - Unframed manuscript 2, April 15, 1961, 14 in. x 11 in. or smaller (certificate and mat) (Box-folder 94/2)
      Korson named as a Fellow of the American Folklore Society. Printed certificate (matted), with handwritten additions and blind stamp. A significant amount of the handwriting has faded. Original ID 4:2.
    - Unframed manuscript 3, October 19, 1965, 10 in. x 15 in. (Box-folder 94/3)
      "Machines Only Music Left in Mines," from The Evening Star (Washington, D.C.). Matted newspaper clipping.
    - Unframed manuscript 4, November 10, 1961, 10 in. x 12 in. (including the mat) (Box-folder 94/4)
      Newspaper report on the celebration for the 50th anniversary of the Pottsville Free Library. Matted newspaper clipping (from The Pottsville (Pennsylvania) Republican and clip-service citation.
    - Unframed manuscript 5, December 6, 1949, 9 in. x 12 in. (Box-folder 94/5)
      Korson granted lifetime honorary membership by the Pennsylvania Folk Lore [sic] Society. Printed certificate, with handwritten additions.
    - Unframed manuscript 6, January 7, 1955, 10 in. x 11 1/4 in. (Box-folder 94/6)
      Typed letter (signed) and typed envelope from Carl Sandburg to Korson. The letter and envelope are matted and mounted.
    - Unframed manuscript 7, December 15, 1955, 9 in. x 12 in. (Box-folder 94/7)
      "30 Million TV Fans See Inside of Mine." One-page article from United Mine Workers Journal. Newsprint clipping (received by AFC already laminated).
    - Unframed manuscript 8, June 1946, 12 in. x 9 in. (Box-folder 94/8)
      "The Singing Miners." One-page article from Junior Bazaar.
    - Unframed manuscript 9, 1949, 8 1/2 in. x 11 in. or smaller (Box-folder 94/9)
      Citation of distinguished service awarded to Korson by the University of Pennsylvania. Printed certificate with handwritten additions. Original ID 4:2.
    - Unframed manuscript 10, January 22, 1965, 9 in. x 7 in. or smaller (for the letter) (Box-folder 94/10)
      Typed letter (signed) and typed envelope from John L. Lewis to Korson.
    - Oversize certificate 1, June 25, 1949, 13 in. x 10 1/2 in. or smaller (Box-folder 94/11)
      Certificate awarded to Korson, granting him associate member status in the Pennsylvania German Society. Printed certificate with handwritten additions and foil seal.
    - Oversize certificate 2, September 15, 1968, 17 in. x 13 3/4 in. or smaller (Box-folder 94/12)
      Certificate awarded (posthumously) to Korson, on the Golden Jubilee of his service during World War I in the Jewish Zealand; presented by the Zionist Organization of America. Printed certificate with handwritten additions.
    - Small poster, circa 1965, 14 in. x 11 in. (Box-folder 94/13)
      Illustrated page, possibly from United Mine Workers Journal, with images of United Mine Workers of America International presidents, 1890-1965. Coated heavy-stock paper, with black marker added over three images. See box-folder 28/7 for a photocopy (received with the collection).
    - Black rock (page proofs), circa 1960, 10 3/4 in. x 13 or smaller (each page) (Box-folder 94/14)
      Printed pages, with handwritten notations. About 100 pages.
  - Subseries P: Maps
    - Map of the Swartara coal region, by Henry K. Strong, circa 1838, 32 in. x 47 in. or smaller (Oversize folder 1/1)
      Printed map; black ink on white paper, possibly a lithograph. The date of the printing is probably much later than the date on the map itself. Accompanied by a county map of Pennsylvania (8 1/2 in. x 11 in.), which originally accompanied it when received from King's College.
    - Literary map of Pennsylvania, 1959, 25 1/4 in. x 38 in. or smaller (Oversize folder 1/2)
      Published by the Pennsylvania Council of Teachers of English. 1959 is the copyright date. Blue and orange printing on white paper.
    - West end of Schuykill County, Pennsylvania, January 1938, 14 in. x 20 1/2 in. or smaller (Oversize folder 1/3)
      Handwriting and notations on both sides of the map, including a typed note to Korson from Carl Maurer, who sent the map to him. Printed map; black ink on white paper, with black ink spill marks along some formerly folded areas at center.
    - Schuylkill and neighboring counties, Pennsylvania, 21 in. x 46 in. or smaller (Oversize folder 1/4)
      Probably a map of mines in Schuylkill and neighboring counties in Pennsylvania. White print on blue background.
    - County and town map, Pennsylvania, 22 in. x 34 in. (Oversize folder 1/5)
      Half the item's 34-inch measurement is the map, and the other half is a location index for counties, cities, and towns
  - Subseries Q: Index card file for books and magazines
    - Index cards (Box-folder 95)
      Original index cards for published books in the George Korson Folklore Archive. Approximately 625 cards. See Appendix A for a list of books retained with the current collection.
  - Subseries R: Angus K. Gillespie research files
    Files donated by Professor Angus K. Gillespie to Rutgers University, documenting his research regarding Korson and Korson's work, for the book Folklorist of the Coal Fields. The original order of the files, as they were received at AFC, has been retained.
    - Transfer of Gillespie papers, September 27, 1990 (Box-folder 96/1)
      One item of correspondence from Ronald L. Becker (Rutgers University) to an unidentified person at King's College, to document that he would ship the Gillespie papers to King's College for inclusion in the George Korson Folklore Archive.
    - Out-of-print book searches, 1972 (Box-folder 96/2)
      Correspondence from Books-On-File (book search service) to Gillespie.
    - Correspondence - Exposition Books, Ltd., 1974-1975 (Box-folder 96/3)
      Correspondence between Gillespie and the publisher of his book on Korson, plus an announcement for the 1974 James Mooney Award. Original file heading: Publication.
    - Red Cross, 1946; 1970 (Box-folder 96/4)
      Research on the Red Cross
    - Reviews and research (1 of 9), 1936 (Box-folder 96/5)
      Photocopies of a review of The miner sings, by Melvin LeMon and George Korson (published 1936), plus a letter dated May 8, 1936 from LeMon to Eugene H. Fischer.
    - Reviews and research (2 of 9), 1926-1928; undated (Box-folder 96/6)
      Photocopies of contemporary reviews of Korson's book Songs and ballads of the anthracite miner (published 1937), with a typed paragraph introducing the material.
    - Reviews and research (3 of 9), 1938-1966; undated (Box-folder 96/7)
      Photocopies of contemporary reviews of Korson's book Minstrels of the mine patch (published 1938), plus pages from the book, with handwritten annotations, and a paper submitted by a student in a class taught by Gillespie.
    - Reviews and research (4 of 9), 1938-1939 (Box-folder 96/8)